他是罗素·博彻特  电脑天才
This is Russell Borchert, computer genius,
今日时尚  明日黄花
反除臭剂积极分子  百万富翁
Anti-deodorant activist, and millionaire.
发明了9轨磁带  因被8轨磁带厂商买通
He was rich for having invented the 9-track cassette,
不要声张而一夜暴富
which the 8-track industry paid to keep quiet.
把所得资产倾注给格林德尔电脑学校
He funneled that wealth into a computer school called Greendale,
在这里他继续研究新项目
Where he obsessively pursued a new project,
一台可以处理情感的机器
a machine that can process feelings.
这些电路明显都是金子造的
He apparently used nothing but gold to assemble his circuitry,
他觉得金可以更好传导人类情感
Believing it to be a better conductor of human emotion.
那个诡异的时代  仿生女得了个艾美奖
It was a weird time. The bionic woman won an Emmy.
他与机器恋爱的谣言四起
Rumors spread about his relationship with computers,
突然有一天  他消失了
And one day, he disappeared,
因首位死于电脑病毒  他成为传奇
Hence the legend that he died of the first computer virus.
政府买下学校  生活继续
The city bought the campus, and life went on.
他的遗体和巨额财富的下落都成了谜
His body was never found, nor was his immense wealth.
有人说
Some people said he hid his money
他把钱藏在了另一个次元
using a portal to another dimension.
那些人都是嗑了药的
Those people were on lsd.
还有人说
Everyone else said
他的办公室里有个秘密金库
He had a secret vault in his office.
-那他的办公室在哪  -问得好
- Well, where's his office? - Good question.
我们找到了这个忏悔书
We found this confession
是格林德尔首位院长写的
written by Greendale's first dean.
「为保护学生的健康以及学校名誉
"To protect the student health and the school's reputation,
我下令封锁了计算机系
"I have sealed off the computer department
并将通往该区域的楼梯拆除」
And removed the stairwell to that entire section."
这让我想到  无人踏足过的
A section that remains on this campus somewhere,
这片神秘区域
its secrets untouched,
有可能藏有博彻特的百万财富
including quite possibly Borchert's millions.
如果我们找到了
If we found it,
可以先于赛百味  从政府手里买下学校
We could buy it from the city before Subway.
此地就可以让我为所欲为了
Then I could really go nuts with this place.
通常这种冒险是我逼大家去的
This is the kind of adventure I usually have to force upon us,
这次可是送上门了
and here it is, falling into our laps.
这就像「七宝奇谋」
We're like the Goonies,
不过我们的故事更有逻辑性
except our story tracks logically
还有机会测试我们的安保水平
and has a chance of holding up to objective critical scrutiny.
-你先等等好吧  -对不起
- Can you please stop that?  - Sorry.
这是你的蓝图  不好意思来晚了
Here are your blueprints. Sorry it took so long.
跟政府斗真是没完没了
You can't fight city hall.
显然你可以  所以才墨迹了这么长时间
Apparently you can. That's why it took so long.
我可整不明白了  你能看懂吗
Well, I'll be damned. Would you look at that?
现在就清楚了
It's so clear now.
学校的整体像个小鸡鸡
The entire school is shaped like a penis.
不是  那个
No, that.
此处称有楼梯通往第三层
It says right here that this stairway leads to sublevel three.
这是不是教师休息室吗
Is that where the teachers' lounge is?
你的鸡鸡是个什么型啊
What the hell does your penis look like?
一堆建筑物型
Obviously a cluster of buildings,
让我们使劲嘲笑怪胎吧
So let's all have a big laugh at the freak.
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：大菜等下季害来木哈哈
翻译：Nova
翻译：大卫熊
翻译：独醉
时间轴：Poxle
校对：大内拖稿太监夕橙橙
后期：御前带喵侍卫鱼骨头
总监：夕橙
废柴联盟
第五季第十三集[季终]·感谢观看
#Six Seasons and A Movie#
失踪的楼梯应该就在这个区域
The missing stairwell would be in this area.
眼睛都睁大了找
Keep your eyes peeled.
虽然我不懂  但连环杀手和藏宝人
I don't know why, but serial killers and people that
都会留下奇怪的线索
hide treasure always leave weird little clues.
看这里
Check it out.
看看这个抱着酒瓶子的
Look at the bottle held by the school's
学校首位勉强接受的吉祥物
first and least acceptable mascot,
大醉鬼
Big Chief drunky.
X标记的地方  亲爱的
X marks the spot, baby.
你最好先别...好吧
Maybe you shouldn't be-- okay.
雪瑞  请把门锁上
Shirley, will you lock the door?
好的
Okay.
可以了
There you go.
只是一堆电线
It's just a bunch of wires.
显然是想迷惑我们
Exactly what they want us to think.
老天爷啊
Oh, my God.
等等等等等
Wait, wait, wait.
火星也许会指引出下一个线索
The sparks may be spelling out the next clue.
邓肯还好吗
Is Duncan okay?
死不了
He'll live,
估计最近吃什么都是焦女味了
but his food's gonna taste like burnt aluminum for a while.
那叫铝
It's pronounced "Al-u-minium."
-你看我说他没事  -行了  都住手吧
- See, he's fine. - Okay, guys, stop it now.
没人想承认要结束了
Nobody wants to admit its over,
可是拜托了
But come on.
哎呦  这不是杰夫·翁格  欢乐警察
Oh, look, it's Jeff Winger, fun police,
谁有微笑就喊停车靠边
Here to pull over our smiles
就因为我们的嘴巴好像贴膜太厚的车窗
'cause our mouths have tinted windows.
我和布雷塔要结婚了
Britta and I are getting married.
-啥  -结婚
- What? - Married?
那你们可要再多弄点鸽子了
Well, you're gonna need way more doves than this.
你看这里像什么
What does this look like,
办公室里的一小时剧集吗
an hour-long episode of the office?
这边挥着锄头  那边电流嗞嗞的
There's pick-axing and electric zapping.
别想承认这些  我们根本就不准备承认
Don't even acknowledge it. We are not acknowledging this.
你们俩这搭配也太离谱了
You guys are ridiculous together.
我俩离谱  那你说这叫啥
We're ridiculous? What do you call this?
-秘密活板门  -吃屎吧
- Secret trapdoor!  - Booyah.
谁有绳子
Who's got rope?
这个问题冒犯到我了
I'm offended by that question.
我们是校董会的里奇和卡尔
This is Richie and Carl from the school board.
没听错  我俩也是有名的人
That's right. We got names.
马上把门打开
Open this door now.
等下  我知道钥匙在哪
Wait, I know where the keys are.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
等我们自己进去  你们麻烦就大了
When we get there, you're gonna be in big trouble.
钥匙来了  钥匙来了
Here they are. Here they are.
哪一把
Which one is it?
第一把永远都不对
Well, it's never the first one,
可以排除这一把了
so we can cancel this one out.
快点
Come on.
现在这是第一把了
I guess now this is the first one,
所以是下一把
so it should be the next one.
-该死的  -听我说
- Oh, damn. - You know what?
我有主意了  把地方给我让出来
I got it. Get out of the way.
-里奇  小心点儿  -别担心
- Richie, be careful.  - Don't worry.
酒喝得够足了
I've been drinking.
你们好啊  来喝点茶吗
Oh, hello. Would you like some tea?
这茶不错哦
The tea is swell.
-你觉得他们...  -嘘
- Do you think they...  - Shh.
-我觉得...  -嘘
- I think--  - Shh.
-够了  嘘  -嘘
- Oh, come on, shh.  - Shh.
这声音大到...
You know it's just as loud as--
都给老娘闭嘴
Everybody, shut up!
这里是格林德尔被遗忘的角落
Guys, I think this is the lost section of Greendale.
从七十年代起  就没人来过这里
Nobody's been in here since the '70s.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
因为辩论赛的辩题是「谁更性感
Because the debate team topic is "Who's hotter,
艾略特·古尔德还是唐纳德·萨瑟兰」
Elliot Gould or Donald Sutherland?"
均为1970年代知名男演员  前者曾出演「老友记」莫妮卡之父
后者曾参演冯小刚的「大腕」
唐纳德·萨瑟兰
Donald sutherland.
-好吓人  -蛋定
- Scary. - Oh, relax.
如果这里只是普通的地牢
If it's anything like a regular dungeon,
那它不会比邀请你来的人更可怕
It's only as dangerous as whoever invited you.
阿布蒂  要是这里有机器人杀手
Abed, if there's killer robots down here,
你会告诉他们我们和你是同伙对吧
You'll tell them we're on your side, right?
没错  但机器人杀手与普通机器人很难区分
Yes, but we won't know them from ordinary robots
除非他们出手
Until they kill us.
-我们现在该怎么办  -分散活动
- So what do we do now? - Split up.
清除所有七十年代的印迹
Leave no '70s reference unturned.
那个年代对我来说有点陌生
This decade's a little out of my wheelhouse.
宠物石...所有宠物石都要检查一遍
Pet rock...leave no pet rock unturned.
可被当作宠物饲养的石头  曾在七十年代风靡一时
我来带路吧  我的灯更亮
Here, let me lead. My light's better.
你的灯更亮么
Your light's better?
你的安全感缺乏到要强调你的灯更亮吗
You're that insecure that your light has to be better?
-闭嘴  -你才闭嘴
- Shut up. - You shut up.
发现什么了吗
Anything in there?
也被称为「豆袋椅」  七十年代的时代象征之一
就是些蜘蛛网与懒人沙发
Just spider webs and beanbag chairs.
别哭了
Oh, don't cry.
支撑腰椎的重要性没有被...
The importance of lumbar support hadn't...
不是因为这个啦
It's not that.
即使我们拯救了格林德尔
It's just even if we do save Greendale,
它也早已不是曾经的格林德尔了
which Greendale will we be saving?
先是皮尔斯死了  再是特洛伊离开了
First Pierce dies. Then Troy leaves.
-现在他们又要...-结婚
- Now people are... - Getting married?
安妮  听着  我不了解人类
Annie, look, I don't know people,
但我熟知电视剧的运作
But I know TV.
当角色预感自己出演的剧集将要被砍
When characters feel like the show they're on is ending,
他们会本能地想通过衍生剧求自保
Their instinct is to spin off into something safer,
就杰夫和布雷塔来说
In Jeff and Britta's case,
如果要保证至少有六集
Something that would last six episodes
而且要有很多关于镊子和麸质的争吵
And have a lot of bickering about tweezers and gluten,
主演必须是他们和另一对白人棕发夫妇
Starring them and an equally WASPY
剧集的名字就叫「阴差阳错嫁对郎」
Brunette couple with a title like Better with My Worse Half
或者叫「糟糕的婚约」或是「永结异心」
or Awfully Wedded or Tying the Not,
「永结同心」的「同」换成「异」
But "Knot" is spelt without a k,
-或是「热门婚姻困局」  -阿布蒂
- or Hot Topics Couple People Problems... - Abed.
而且每一集里有...
and every episode, you get...
-阿布蒂  阿布蒂  别脑补了  -抱歉
- Abed. Abed, stop developing. - Sorry.
安妮  我想说的是  这部剧
The point is, this show, Annie,
并不只关于他们
it isn't just their show.
这也是我们的剧  而且还没被砍呢
This is our show, and it's not over.
我们越快找到那些宝藏
And the sooner we find that treasure,
杰夫布雷塔的夫妇剧试播集就会越早被砍
the faster the Jeff-Britta pilot falls apart.
-我懂了  谢谢你阿布蒂  -不用谢
- Got it. Thank you, Abed. - You're welcome.
-哥是有女朋友的  -什么
- I have a girlfriend. - What?
你打算来段吻戏是吧
You were about to start a kiss lean.
-我才没有  -那就好
- I was not. - Fine.
我们去找宝藏吧
Let's go find treasure.
-你们发现什么了吗  -没有
- Did you find anything? - No.
这里的每一处裂缝我们都搜过了
We've searched every crevice of this place,
找到的唯一「宝藏」只有民用波段无线电
And the only treasures we've found are this cb radio,
白人篮球运动员的卡片
These basketball cards with white people on them,
还有这只玩具火箭发射器
And this little rocket launcher from some action figure.
作为死胡同来说  这里很古怪
Seems like an odd place for a dead end, though.
可能会有一扇暗门
Could be a secret door.
这台点唱机或许就是开门的机关
Maybe the jukebox is the key to it.
大家别忘了  即使失败也没关系
Just remember, it's okay if we fail.
-对吧  杰夫  -没错
- Right, Jeff? - That's right.
恶心  试试所有按钮吧
Agh, try every button.
每个都按一遍试试
Just try every single button ever.
-你没事吧  -当然有事  我快死了
- Are you all right? - No! I was dying!
-试试第127首歌  -没错
- Try track 127. - Right.
127译成二进制代码后是个回文序列
Because 127 in binary code would be a palindrome.
因为这首歌名叫「开启暗门吧」
Because the song title is Open the Door by The Secret Doors.
-开门吧  -欧耶
- Open the door  - Yeah
-我们要开门啦  -门开啦
- We got to open the door  - And the door is opening
我们的歌能开门哟
You're the playing the song that opens the door
录下这歌就为帮你开门哟
We recorded this song for when you open the door
为配合大门开启的过程
Specially timed to the duration
特别剪辑的哟
Of the opening process
博歇特的秘密机房
Borchert's secret lab.
那是影片里博歇特使用的机器
That's the machine Borchert was working on in the film.
这是博歇特的「宝藏」
Borchert's gold.
我们得把它运到楼上去
We need to get this upstairs.
拯救格林德尔
Save Greendale.
别慌  别慌  别慌
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
你就是罗素·博歇特  对吧
You're Russell Borchert, aren't you?
我得告诉你一些残酷的现实
Hey, I'm gonna peel off some band-aids here.
好莱坞知名演员与导演
丹尼斯·霍珀已经死了
Dennis hopper is dead,
电视节目不再使用主题曲
TV shows give no time for theme songs anymore,
伍迪·艾伦为一只卡通蚂蚁配了音
And Woody Allen did the voice of a cartoon ant.
伍迪·艾伦在「蚁哥正传」中为主角配音
杰夫
Jeff!
抱歉  我忘记自己有多强壮了
Sorry, I lose track of how big I'm getting.
我不会忘记
I don't.
你们故意破坏私有财产
You vandalized private property.
你们差点就毁了这所学校
You nearly destroy the school
我们好不容易才开始有点盈利
When it's finally about to make a profit?
你们这帮家伙最差劲
You guys are the worst,
老是玩些彩弹游戏  木头人游戏
With your stupid paintballs and your freeze tags.
-那个叫熔岩游戏  -熔岩游戏么
- Hot lava. - That was hot lava?
名字真蠢
Dumb.
快说其他人去哪儿了
Tell us where the others went.
我说...
Guys, guys.
-你打算怎么办  -我们能怎么办
- What do you want to do? - What should we do?
我们能做些什么
Well, what can we do?
好吧
Okay.
你们俩不要插手
I'm gonna need you guys to stay back
而且要对今天的所见永远保密
And never tell anyone about what you saw here today.
里奇  你很特别  你的脑袋很特别
You're special, Richie. Your mind is special.
你知道你与其他小盆友不一样
You know it works differently from other kids' minds.
里奇是怪胎
Richie's a freak
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道他们去哪儿了
I know where they went.
他们从窗口爬上了屋顶
They climbed out a window to the roof,
跳上滑翔机
hopped on a hang glider,
飞到那个希腊餐馆
and flew it across town to that Greek restaurant,
克里斯托老爹
Papa Cristo's?
我盗梦了  盗走了
I robbed your brain. I robbed it.
伙计们  我们在自动贩卖机
Hey, guys, we found a hatch in the floor
下面找到了一个活板门
underneath the vending machine.
我认为他们进去了
I think they went down inside it.
那里有滑翔机吗
Was there a hang glider?
你会找到
You're gonna find out--
你在下面会发现滑翔机
You're gonna find a hang glider down there.
我确定
That much I know.
总之呢  我把自己关在下面
So anyway, I sealed myself up down here
储存了够吃五十年的食物  够用五十年的厕纸
with 50 years of food, 50 years of toilet paper,
还有够吸五十年的可卡因
and 50 years of cocaine,
不知怎么  十年后就被我吸光了
which I somehow ran out of after about 10 years.
-哇喔  80年代在这里也发生了  -是啊
- Wow, the '80s happened down here too. - Yeah.
你们在对拉奎尔做什么
Hey, what are you doing with Raquel?
罗素  我们赶时间
Russell, we're on a bit of a deadline,
说得直白点  我们需要你的宝藏
and to put it bluntly, we need your gold.
-拉奎尔  -伙计们  帮帮忙
- Raquel! - Uh, guys, little help--
她只需要一点时间
She just needs a little more time.
拉奎尔占据了你最棒的一段人生
Sir, Raquel has taken the best years of your life
还有许多不怎么样的人生
and a dozen of your not-so-good.
如果她没给你回报
If she hasn't given anything back,
是时候向前看了
it might be time to move on.
住手  伙计们  我们这是在干什么
Stop. You guys, what are we doing?
-拯救格林德尔  -如何拯救
- Saving Greendale. - From what?
我们被恶人卑劣的价值观逼到这里
We were driven down here by sellouts with crappy values.
从什么时候开始  人们开始决定
Since when do human beings decide
哪些梦想是有价值的  哪些没有
which dreams are worthwhile?
看看他啊  他跟我们一样
Look at him. He's one of us.
我们得尊重对方
We have to respect each other enough
允许彼此做自己想做的事
to let each other want what we want,
不管我们的自毁倾向有多么明显
No matter how transparently self-destructive
不过我们的欲望有多空洞
or empty our desires may be.
如果你们要钱
If it was money that you guys wanted,
直接说啊
why didn't you say so?
直接去我桌子下面
You can just have my leftover cash
拿点我的零花钱就好
that's under the desk over there.
它们可能不值太多钱
Yeah, I don't think it's worth much up there.
-那是杰拉尔德·福特美元  -有多少
- Those are Gerald Ford dollars. - How many?
两百万吧
Eh, couple of million.
70年代时  这些老值钱了
Back in the '70s, that was worth millions.
我有个主意
Hey, I've got an idea.
你们别来烦我
How about you people leave me alone
这些钱我就赠给格林德尔
and I hereby grant that to Greendale?
很高兴听到这个消息
Glad to hear it.
什么
What?
退后  这个腌黄瓜是个磁石
Get back. This pickle's a magnet.
-别激动  -我吸死她
- Whoa, whoa. - I'll wipe her out, man.
别用腌黄瓜
Don't you dare use that pickle--
过去跟他们站一起
Get over there with them.
你没权拿走那些钱
You have no legal claim to that money.
等托管结束一小时后
Take it up with Subway in about an hour
你们找赛百味去算账吧
after close of escrow.
昌  你又变成反派了吗
Hey, Chang, you've become a bad guy again?
我可不只是反派  布雷塔
There's a lot more to it than that, Britta.
等下  我没戴面具吗
Wait, I'm not wearing a mask?
好吧  我想我只是精神病而已
Okay, there's no more to it. I think I'm just mentally ill.
退后  听见没
All right, just stay back. All right?
不要
No, don't.
不
No!
美人
Yeah, sweet mama.
门关上了
The door is closing
-比打开时还快  -为了戏剧冲突
- Faster than it opens . - For dramatic effect
坚持住
Hang in there.
拉奎尔是主操作系统
Raquel is the main operating system.
她控制门  灯光
She controls the door, the lights,
可能还有淋浴  一切
the shower probably, everything,
现在她死了
and now she's dead.
这么说我们被困在这了
So we're trapped in here forever.
直到我们的水和食物用光
Or just until we run out of food and water.
至少我们还有彼此
At least we'll have each other.
只有死亡才能将我们分离
Till death do us part.
擦  我的水和食物都给你们算了
You know what? You guys can have my food and water.
拉奎尔  加油  活过来
Come on, Raquel. Come on.
宝贝  求你了
Baby. Come on.
感谢上帝
Oh, thank God.
她的情感部件还好用
Her emotional components are still on-line.
情感部件
Emotional components?
我在这里取得的成就
I have accomplished things down here
你们都无法想象
you couldn't even possibly imagine.
我秀给你们看
Here, let me show you.
看见没  看见没
Ah, right there! That was it.
就是那个  看见了吗
That was it. Did you see it?
不懂吗  这计算机能回应感情
Don't you see? This computer responds to feelings.
我创建格林德尔的时候  是为了让普通人
When I started Greendale, it was for ordinary people
接触到科技
to be able to access technology.
等等  你创建了格林德尔
Wait, you started greendale.
你有什么文件吗
Do you have that in writing anywhere?
不清楚  在那边那坨破烂里可能有
I don't know. Somewhere with all that crap over there.
但是没了情感部件
But without an emotional component,
计算机将剔除我们的人性
computers would strip us of all humanity
创建一个
and create a society
无情的人做主导
with emotionless eggheads at the top
有情的白痴遭沦落的社会
and idiots with feelings at the bottom,
我拒绝让那样的事情发生  所以我
and I refuse to let that happen, and that's why I've spent--
干啥  这是什么
What? What is that?
小猫的视频
It's a video of a kitten.
这些人干嘛要争论
And why are those people arguing about it?
那是什么
And what's that?
表情符号
That's an emoticon.
那人想要表达快乐
That person wants to indicate happiness
但无法用语言表达
but can't convey it with language,
于是他们错用标点组成笑脸
so they misuse punctuation to form a smile.
太他喵的...
That is so...
蠢
stupid.
只有白痴才会那么做
Only an idiot would think of this.
白痴赢了
Idiots won,
意味着我在这里的任务也结束了
which means my work down here is done.
很好  根据我看到的东西
Good, because according to what I'm seeing,
如果我们能把你带上去
if we can get you up there right now,
赛百味就买不了我们的学校了
Subway won't be buying this school.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
但要几个小时
Uh, yeah, but it's gonna take a few hours
才能打开门
to get that door open,
因为拉奎尔的逻辑电路
because Raquel's logic circuits--
不太利索
Bleh, not good.
你说她的情感部件还是好的
You said her emotional components work.
理论上
Well, in theory,
人类情感的爆发
a blast of human passion
可以将主机震撼到冷启动
could shock the mainframe into a cold start,
但那只能是各位之中
but that's only if somebody in this room
有人能产生比我摸乳头时更强烈的感觉才行
has feelings stronger than I get when I rub my nipples,
祝各位好运了
So good luck with that, folks.
我来试试
Give me that.
所有人转身
Everybody over there. Turn around.
马上转身
Turn around now.
你是来救我的  对吗
You're here to save me, aren't you?
我们出去之后别再回头
Let's get out of here and never look back.
杰夫  万一你一定要对我念念不忘
Jeff, in case you ever have to remember me,
我给一些旁白经典词的建议好吗
can I give you some options for voice-over quotes?
闭嘴  阿布蒂
Shut up, Abed.
-女士  -大人
- Milady. - Milord.
你做了什么
What did you do?
别管这个  我们快走
Don't worry about it. Let's go.
格林德尔市深感骄傲
The city of Greendale is proud
格林德尔大学即将出售给赛百味
to be selling the school of Greendale to Subway.
这样便终结了多年来
This brings to an end several years
克拉格·伊西多尔·派尔顿院长的糟糕管理
of horrible management by dean Craig Isidore Pelton.
不是说现在找人背黑锅
Not to throw anyone under the bus,
但要背只有他了
but he'd be the one.
我的表显示
And by my watch,
是时候签署文件
it is about time to sign these documents
正式生效
and make it official.
反对
Objection!
我在格林德尔教法律
I teach law at Greendale,
所以相信我  对于法律我懂得不多
so believe me, I don't know much about law,
但看到合同违约时我还是知道的
but I do know a contract violation when I see one.
这是市里将学校
This is a legitimate transaction
出售给餐厅的合法交易
where a city is selling a school to a restaurant.
这种事情每天在各地均有发生
it happens somewhere every day.
市里想怎么卖学校都行
Oh, the city can sell the school all it wants,
但根据学校创办人与市里的合约
but according to his contract with the city,
对于未来所有发生的学校事件
the school's original founder retains the privilege of consultation
学校创办人都有商讨权
on all future scholastic endeavors taking place here.
赛百味三明治大学
So Subway Sandwich University,
来见见你们的新副院长罗素·博歇特吧
meet your new vice dean, Russell Borchert.
你好  看来我们要做合伙人了
Hi, I guess we're gonna be partners.
我知道有个叫互联网的东西
I understand there's some internet
可以将我的思想公开
where I can make my inner thoughts public.
看来格林德尔市
It seems like Greendale the city
与格林德尔大学还有些问题要解决
and Greendale the school have some stuff to sort out,
赛百味不喜欢置身矛盾中
and Subway doesn't-- doesn't do conflict.
美味食物及优惠价格才是我们的追求
We do good food at good prices.
我们只是单纯的三明治艺术家
We are but simple sandwich artists
希望全世界都能新鲜饮食每一天
who want the world to eat fresh.
新鲜饮食每一天
Eat fresh!
赛百味  开路
Subway, ho!
我们刚刚拯救了格林德尔吗
Did we just save Greendale?
不  你们没有
No, no, you did not.
我们只是给格林德尔的坟墓松松了土
You moved dirt around Greendale's grave.
你们学校依然濒临破产  依然没有市场价值
Your school is still bankrupt, it is still unmarketable,
依然永远是以后任何一个
and it is still on the permanent chopping block
掌权者砧板上的鱼肉
of anyone who has any say in its future.
是吗
Yeah?
在这里  我们管这个叫「轻松周三」
Well, around here, we call that Wednesday.
我触电身亡之后
Hey, after I was electrocuted,
你俩是不是说了要结婚
didn't you two say you were gonna get married?
触电就表示死了  说身亡太累赘
Doesn't electrocuted technically mean killed?
你总是会这样纠正别人吗
Do you always have to correct people like that?
你总是会对纠正出言指责吗
Do you always have to police correcting?
够了  婚姻取消
That's it. The marriage is off.
你是说婚礼取消吧
I think you mean the wedding is off.
-对了  -不错
- Yeah! - Hey, hey.
我得说
Hey, I got to say,
在审讯中你表现太好了
you held up well under that interrogation.
我跟你说件事
I'm gonna tell you something
这是我们的秘密
that I'd like to stay between us.
我当时在想滑翔机
I was thinking about a hang glider.
任何矛盾都不重要
None of this conflict truly matters.
这片土地唯一的主人是阿拉巴霍人
the only owners of this land are the Arapaho.
如果我请你教我运用法术
Would it offend you if I asked you
这是对你的冒犯吗
to train me in the use of certain powers?
抱歉  卡尔  你壮志未酬
Sorry, Carl. You deserve better.
昌  你最懂我
Chang, you get it.
想在学校董事会谋一职位吗
How would you like a job on the school board?
好的
Okay.
你的第一项工作就是送这个
Your first job is to deliver this
去市财务室
to the city bursar's office.
马上去
On it.
是的  我要把全部牙齿换成钻石的
Hi, yes, I'd like to replace all my teeth with diamonds.
我们养精蓄锐  择日再战
We live to fight another day.
说到日子  我从来没有机会祝你
Speaking of days, I never got a chance to wish you
生日快乐  万圣节或圣诞节快乐
a happy birthday or Halloween or Christmas
没祝过你任何节日快乐
or any specific calendar event.
-那就明年再说  -绝对的
- Well, maybe next year. - Definitely.
我们明年绝对会回来的
We'll definitely be back next year.
如果没有  那是因为小行星
If not, it'll be because an asteroid
毁灭了人类文明
has destroyed all human civilization,
这其实是原设定
and that's canon.
什么  你在看...
What? What are you--
没什么
Nothing.
拯救格林德尔  完成
我想的和你想的一样吗
Am I thinking what you're thinking?
思想者杰克
告诉我你在想什么
Penny for your thoughts.
NBC台周四晚  新剧一览
重症凯伦
Intensive Karen.
埃及先生
Mr. Egypt.
名人节奏
Celebrity Beat-off.
大厨船长
Captain Cook.
今年夏季
或秋季
也可能是明年冬季
视被砍节目而定
Depends on what fails.